Guide to the Edwin P. Kilroe Papers 1832-1950 (bulk, 1890s-1948) MS 3125
New-York Historical Society
- Various, 1922-1938 (Offsite-box 29)
  * Notebook with alphabetical list by name of country houses. 1922. It is not clear how this fits with the collection, and there is no explicit reference to Kilroe in it, so it may have gotten mixed in by mistake over time.
- World War I era scrapbooks, 1900-1919 (Offsite-box 30)
  This box holds scrapbooks with "War records" of Thomas Francis Kilroe and James Vincent Kilroe (Edwin's brothers). Holds cards, menus, orders, correspondence (including letters home to their mother). 3 volumes + an envelope of documents.
- World War I era books and other documents, 1914-1920 (Offsite-box 31)
  * World War I sheet music and ephemera, circa 1917-20
  * Serial publication "Deeds that thrill the empire," Parts 1-7, circa 1916-18, published in London by Hutchinson & Co.
  * Issue of magazine "La rire," circa 1914 (in French)
  * Issue of "Comoedia illustre," December 1913 (in French)
  * 6 issues of "Book News Monthly," (1915)
  * Book "History of the 77th Division" (1919)
  * "The Plattsburger" [military training camp yearbook-like publication], circa 1917
  * Packet of photographs labeled on envelope as "German war pictures seized July 18, 1918". Most are not captioned. Some taken by International Press Exchange. Photos of troops, officers, hospitals, etc.
  * Memorandum book of Thomas Kilroe re: World War I service
  * Notebook of Thomas Kilroe. This pertains to his work as electrician for Edison Company.
  * 9 small military instruction manuals, 1914-17
  * Carbon copy of "registration list of all males registered on June 5, 1917 between the ages of 21-30 inclusive" [in Wayne County, Pennsylvania]
- Documents re: 20th Century Fox Film Corp., 1930-1940s (Offsite-box 32)
  * Photographs: many still shots and publicity shots from 4 movies: "Wilson," "When Irish eyes are smiling," "Greenwich Village," and "Sweet Rosie O'Grady"
  * Scripts for "Greenwich Village": "Shooting final" (10/19/43) and "Continuity & dialogue taken from the screen" (8/21/44)
  * Scripts for "When Irish eyes are smiling": "Revised temporary," stamped "final" (2/3/44) and "Continuity & dialogue taken from the screen" (10/18/44)
  * Scripts for "Sweet Rosie O'Grady": "Shooting final" (2/19/43) and "Continuity & dialogue taken from the screen" (10/1/43)
  * Scripts for "Wilson": "4th revised shooting final" (11/13/43) and "Continuity & dialogue taken from the screen" (9/11/44)
  * Correspondence re: copyright of the title "The Arizona Kid" (1930)
  * Correspondence re: degree of fact and fiction in E.E. Hale's "A man without a country" (1943)
  * Miscellaneous letters, press releases, news items, etc. re: 20th Century Fox (1940s)
- Accordion folders. Letters A-E, 1941-1948 (Offsite-box 33)
  * Folder A: "Greeting cards--holiday cards, menus and programs, 1944, 1945"
  * Folder B: "Greeting cards--holiday cards, 1946-October 15, 1948"
  * Folder C: "Correspondence: Mr. Everly (1941); Mabel Walker Willebrandt (1941); Backus; Prices at Sale (July 22, 1944); Holstein-Friesian World (August 1, 1942); Price slips of purchases made by Edwin P. Kilroe; Carnation herd, catalogue, correspondence, statements of Mabel Walker Willebrandt (1941-1947)" Generally, this appears to relate to Wayne County, the farm, and cattle breeding.
  * Folder D: "Clergy-masses; Reverend Peter S. Kane; 40th anniversary of Kane (June 22, 1948); Order of the Cenacle (1948); Bishop's Committee of the Laity (1942-48)"
  * Folder E: "Trip to Chicago-American Bar Association (September 1944); Lenox Hill Hospital (1946); Trip to Cuba (February 9-26, 1947); Trip to Sarasota, Florida (January 2-February 5, 1948)" The Cuba trip likely refers to his interview with Ernest Hemingway on a 20th Century Fox legal matter, but there appears to be no relevant documents here except for trip vouchers and the like.
- Accordion folders. Letters F-J, 1941-1950 (Offsite-box 34)
  * Folder F: "Reverend James M. Kilroe Papers--Correspondence." This folder relates to farm history.
  * Folder G: "Sister Sylvia, Marywood College (1941-[1950])"
  * Folder H: "American Irish Historical Society; Society of the Friendly Sons of St. Patrick; United States Catholic Historical Society; Newman Club; Catholic Press Association; Catholic Club of the City of New York. (1944-October 15, 1948)"
  * Folder I: "American Bar Association; New York State Bar Association; New York County Lawyers Association; Association of the Bar of the City of New York; Pennsylvania Bar Association; Wayne County, Pennsylvania, Bar Association" (1944-October 15, 1948)"
- Accordion folders. Letters K-N, Q, 1930s-1948 (Offsite-box 35)
  * Folder K: "Knights of Columbus" 1944-October 15, 1948
  * Folder L: "The Grand Street Boys Association" 1944-October 15, 1948
  * Folder M: "New York Athletic Club" 1944-October 15, 1948
  * Folder N: "Columbia Law News, April 1947-September 1948; Grand Jury panel, Volume 23, No. 1, January 1945; William A. Hildebrand's Jenny Lind collection, correspondence [1930s]." This last concerns Kilroe's attempt to help acquire the Lind collection for a Swedish-American Historical Society.
  * Folder Q: "Columbia University, Columbia U. Club, Alumni Associations" (1944-October 15, 1948)
- Accordion folders. Letters O, P, U, 1938-1948 (Offsite-box 36)
  This box holds 3 thick folders with documentation concerning farms and cattle breeding.
- Accordion folders. Letters R-T and various other subjects, 1937-1948 (Offsite-box 37)
  * Folder R: "Clippings, family and local (1937-October 1948)
  * Folder S: "James V. Kilroe" (1946-48). Concerns James's candidacy for judicial positions, etc.
  * Folder T: "Newspaper clippings, magazine articles, decisions re: Hines case, Moskowitz and Schenck trial" (1939-October 8, 1944)
  * Files from 1948-1950: "Columbia Law; Grand Jury Panel; New York Athletic Club; Knights of Columbus; and Grand Street Boys Association"
- Accordion folders. Various subjects, 1927-1928, 1940s (Offsite-box 38)
  * "Catholic Writers Guild" (1940s)
  * 4 folders re: World War II: Lieutenant Colonel Dr. John C. Kilroe "correspondence from war theatres"; "Colonel Robert H. Kilroe [Edwin's brother] correspondence, cards, souvenirs from battlefronts, North Africa, Sicily, Italy"; leather billfold from Italy, gift from Robert to Edwin, with letter about economic conditions in Italy (1944); "Correspondence from the camps and battlefields of World War II: Dr. Abeloff, Dr. Handelman, Bob Brock, Arnold J. Bernstein, Bill Bratter, William T. Powers"
  * Sarah Doherty Kilroe (died 12/16/1928) and Mary E. Kilroe (died 10/3/1927) "newspaper clipping and receipts"; carbon copy of condolence letters re: Sarah
- Accordion folders. Various subjects, 1866-1950 (Offsite-box 39)
  * "The Bennett farm, costs, sales, 1941-1947"
  * "The Great Flood in Honesdale, Pennsylvania, May 22-23, 1942, newspaper clippings"
  * "40th anniversary of Rev. Peter S. Kane, June 22, 1948"
  * "Honesdale, Bethany, Wayne Co: Newspapers, clippings, maps, miscellaneous items, Dyberry School #3, McCabe execution"
  * "E.A. De Laney, obituary, July 1947"
  * "Fire loss on the McCormick-Deering International combine and threshing machine" (1946)
  * "Farms on road leading to Kilroe Farm, acreage, owners, description"
  * "Religious prejudice in school system, Wayne County, Pennsylvania. Dispute with Superintendent Koehler. Gravity School--Protestant or Catholic" (1915-17)
  * "United Nations report on traffic in women and children, 1948"
  * "The Fenian attack on Canada." This includes an original copy of an August 29, 1866 Canadian newspaper
  * "Wayne County, Pennsylvania, Society of New York, Horace G. Young Prize, Letter from Robert G. Hone" (1910-14)
  * "Wayne County, Pennsylvania, Society of New York" (1911-12)
  * Columbia University Alumni Association and Wrestling, 1948-1950
- Accordion folders. Columbia University, 1902-1940s (Offsite-box 40)
  * Columbia calendars, circa 1902-14
  * Other Columbia subjects include wrestling, alumni associations, Democratic Club, Hall committees (1910-11), University Club
- Accordion folders. Numbered I-XI, 1900s-1940s (Offsite-box 41)
  * Folder I: "Book-plates (1915-29); Brothers of the Book (1916-23); American Book-Plate Society (1916-23); Bibliophile Society (1916-23)"
  * Folder II: "New York Law Institute (1909-14); Pacific Athletic Club (1897); St. Peter's Sodality Lyceum (1899); St. Bridget's Catholic Club (1902); West Side Democratic Club (1912-29); Sherry Democratic Club (1911); Direct Primary League (1910); Napper Tandy Club (1909); Erigena Society (1915); American Commission on Irish Independence (1920); Loyal Order of Moose (1909); Ancient Order of Hibernians (1911); Veteran Corps 69th Regiment (1919)"
  * Folder III: "Speakers Bureau, Tammany Hall (1908-29); New York Young Democratic Club (1915-29); National Democratic Club (1019-29)"
  * Folder IV: "City Club (1916-29); Academy of Political Science (1912-29); Penn. Society; Modern Woodmen of America"
  * Folder V: "Society of the Friendly Sons of St. Patrick" (1930s-40s)
  * Folder VI: "Newman Club; Marquette Club; Catholic Press Association; Catholic Club of the City of New York; United States Catholic Historical Society; American Irish Historical Society" (1900s-40s)
  * Folder VII: "New York Athletic Club" (1920s-30s)
  * Folder VIII: "National Geographic Society; New York State Historical Society: New York Historical Society; Honesdale Golf Club"
  * Folder IX: Four lawyer/bar associations (1920s-40s)
  * Folder X: "Knights of Columbus, 1902-29"
  * Folder XI: "Catholic Writers Guild" (1930s-40s)
  * "Dwight School" (1930s-40s)
- Theatre programs and greeting cards, 1919-1944 (Offsite-box 42)
  This box holds unbound theatre programs (1919-30s) and greeting cards, valentine's, etc. (1940-44).
- Various, 1910-1949 (Offsite-box 43)
  * Greeting cards, 1948-49
  * Membership cards, 1930s-40s, and Kilroe's compiled, lengthy list of memberships, 1894-1944
  * Ephemera, 1910-20s
  * Photostats of letters and copies of table of contents of various bound volumes in the collection
  * Booklet of Kilroe's lecture on copyright legislation, 1944
  * Correspondence, personal (District Attorney's Office), 1920-23
  * Kilroe case documents/Almirall grand jury, 1922
  * Tammany collection documents, 1920s
- Scrapbooks, 1894-1940s (Offsite-box 44)
  One scrapbook that holds mostly clippings, with some correspondence and ephemera (1920s-40s) and one that holds extensive clippings of political parodies and satires (poems, songs, cartoons) and articles about political parodies performed by the Inner Circle, Gridiron Club, and other groups (1894-1936).
- Various, 1918-1920 (Offsite-box 45)
  This box holds documents related to the investigations into the war charities frauds and theatre ticket speculation, and pins, ribbons, and other similar small objects.
- Pictorial works and cartoons re: women, 1930s-1940s (Offsite-box 46)
  This box holds an assortment of pictorial works, some of artworks, but all generally featuring women, especially of cartoons with sexual innuendo and of other images typically associated with so-called men's magazines, such as Esquire. Similar material is also found in box 8. There are also a number of books of photographs along the same lines: "Model beautiful"; "--Model poses"; "--Schonheit des korpers"; "Highlights & shadows"; "Enchanting beauty"; "Nus"; "French models."
- Columbia University publication "Spectator", 1903 May-1906 June (Offsite-box 47)
- Columbia University publication "Spectator", 1906 September-1908 May (Offsite-box 48)
- Columbia University publication "Spectator", 1908 September-1910 January (Offsite-box 49)
- Columbia University publication "Spectator", 1910 January-1911 June (Offsite-box 50)
- Columbia University publication "Spectator", 1911 September-1913 June (Offsite-box 51)
- Columbia University publication "Spectator", 1912 September-1914 May (Offsite-box 52)
- Columbia University publication "Spectator", 1914 September-1915 May (Offsite-box 53)
- Photograph album. Oversize, circa 1890s-1920s (Offsite-box 54)
  The album holds cabinet cards, group portraits, and other photographic formats of Kilroe as a child, on Columbia wrestling teams, at organizational formal dinners, etc. The album is very large and heavy, requiring two people to handle.
- Artifacts, 1907-1923 (Offsite-box 55)
  * Golden Rule Alliance collection box, with some coins and related placard (in connection with war charities frauds)
  * Cripples' Welfare Society collection box, with related placard (in connection with war charities frauds)
  * Cased portrait drawing of an unidentified man
  * Pin cushion
  * Wooden bank
  * "Four mementoes" re: expressions of friendship, 1907-23, at least two from "Ethel" (probably Ethel Peckham, see box 27)
- Movie posters and publicity (Oversize), 1943-1944 (Offsite-box 56)
  Oversize publicity pieces for "Wilson," "When Irish Eyes Are Smiling," "Greenwich Village," and "Sweet Rosie O'Grady"
- Other oversize items, circa 1904-1925 (Offsite-box 56)
  This box holds photographs and other oversize items. Most of these items were framed, but were unfraned for conservation. Frames were deteriorated and discarded.
  * 3 photographs re: Columbia University: Class of 1904, Wrestling team (2), and a drawing and certificate re: basketball.
  * Portait photographs of Lora Lieb (1914), Etta Mylotte(?) (1917), Eleanor Shaw (1919), Kathryn Breslin (1919), children from the Hull family (1925), August Mayer (inscribed), and several of Kilroe, likely from 1930s-40s. Also a panorama photo of the 11th annual banquet of the Wayne County Pennsylvania Society of New York at the Hotel McAlpin, February 8, 1917.
  * 2 photos of a Buick car apparently damaged in an accident (1917).
  * 4 photos of Kilroe's library at 408 Manhattan Ave. (undated)
  * Letter complimenting Kilroe on success in getting a bill regulating speculation in theatre tickets (1918)
  * 3 letters re: Kilroe's appointments to Deputy Assistant District Attorney and Assistant District Attorney (1916, 1918, 1923)
  * 4 boards of mounted newspaper articles: Page from the New York Times of July 20, 1913, re: the history of Tammany Hall; clips re: Kilroe's book on Tammany, 1913; and 2 boards of clips of Kilroe accomplishments, 1913-1919
- Certificates and acknowledgements, 1912-1930 (Offsite-box 56)
  In August 2022, the Wayne County (Penn.) Historical Society (WCHS) donated the following items to N-YHS, which were added to the Kilroe papers. These items, at least in part, had been donated to WCHS by Edwin Kilroe in 1940.
  * Certificate, King's Crown, Columbia College, undated. Signed by Kilroe as Secretary
  * Certificate, National Minute Men Committee of the Democratic National Committee, member, 1912
  * Certificates of election to Democratic Party county committee, 1912, 1919
  * Certificate of admission to bar of U.S. District Court at New Haven, Conn., 1914
  * Certificate, New York County Lawyers Association membership, 1915
  * Notice of membership, New York State Historical Association, 1917
  * Certificate, National Geographic Society membership, 1918
  * Certificate, Mayor's Committee of Welcome to Home-coming Troops, member, 1918-19
  * Certificate, Knights of Columbus life membership, 1925
  * Certificate of admission to the bar of U.S. District Court for Southern District of New York, 1930
  * Two bookplates designed by Kilroe for his library, 1915, 1920